YOGITA NEGI

ynegi6@gmail.com / 44 7393128280 / MILTON KEYNES

Summary

As a passionate front-end developer with a background in Fixed income research analysis and Technical Sales Support, I bring a unique combination of skills to any team.

I have completed a comprehensive Front-end Web Developer at edX bootcamp and developed several successful projects that demonstrate my ability to turn complex ideas into visually stunning web applications.

My greatest strengths include my attention to detail, problem-solving skills, and ability to work collaboratively with others to deliver exceptional results.

Experience

Technical Sales Support

Exchange Data International • London 02/2023

- As a Technical Sales Support at EDI, I am responsible for providing technical support to clients for EDI's core products.
- I actively enhance and develop WCA/WFI Proprietary Feeds, primarily in SQL. My responsibilities also include playing an active role in new product development, trials, and the on-boarding process.
- I ensure maximum coverage at market, country level, asset class level and handle coverage reporting for Sales personnel, data support personnel, data quality personnel, and management.
- Additionally, I assist in troubleshooting/support to our operations in the event of delay/failure of feed delivery.

Fixed Income Support Research Analyst

Exchange Data International • MILTON KEYNES 03/2020 - 01/2023

- As a Fixed Income Support Research Analyst at Exchange Data International, I worked with a team to manage client queries efficiently and effectively.
- I was responsible for owning and managing all Fixed Income queries through ticket and email systems, conducting research on existing and additional sourcing of reference data and corporation actions for Fixed Income securities, and providing support to a key Fixed Income outsourcing project.
- Additionally, I assisted the Fixed Income team in reviewing existing data sources for coverage, quality, and timeliness.
- During my time in this role, I also used my skills in Python to automate certain processes and improve efficiency.

Sr. Operational Operation Analyst

IHS Markit • India 09/2016 - 11/2020

- As a Sr.Operational Operation Analyst, my primary responsibility was to manage and resolve client queries related to fixed income securities by working closely with internal teams such as Operations, Sales, IT, Data providers and Client Support.
- I also conducted research on existing and additional sourcing of reference data and corporation actions for Fixed Income securities, participated in regular team meetings, and acted as the point of escalation for internal team queries. In addition, I was responsible for monitoring data delivery batches, coordinating and resolving challenges raised by clients, integrating new clients and ensuring testing signoff before every release.
- I also used SQL database for data mining and trained new joiners and cross-trained other teams. As an additional responsibility, I also automated certain tasks using Python.

Sr. Financial Data Analyst

Nirvana Solutions • India 07/2012 - 09/2016

As a Senior Financial Data Analyst, my responsibilities included client onboarding and integration, coordinating and communicating with third parties, managing a team of 5 people, handling 9 projects for daily processes, implementing corporate actions, reconciling client activities and portfolios with prime brokers, preparing reports, identifying process improvements, and providing training to new joiners.

I also gained experience in different types of assets classes and advanced proficiency in MS Excel.

Skills

Proficiency in Python programming language, BeautifulSoup, Scrapy, or Selenium, Knowledge of version control systems like Git and GitHub., HTML, CSS, and JavaScript, React, BootStarp, Tailwind CSS

Education

Front End Web Developer

EDX • London 03/2023